Guide to the "Lady's Pictorial" and "The Gentlewoman" Letters, 1884-1917 MS 131
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
"Lady's Pictorial" and "The Gentlewoman" Letters, 1884-1917
1884-03-02-1917-04-04
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Goddard, Arthur
MS 131
0.25 Linear Feet (1 folder containing 64 letters)
This is a collection of 64 letters addressed to Goddard and Wood. Notable correspondents include Edwin Lester Arnold, F.C. Burnand, Hall Caine, Sir F. Carruthers Goulde, Lillie Langtry, Clotilde Graves and Gertrude Kingston.
Biographical Note
Arthur Goddard and J.S. Wood were editors of "Lady's Pictorial" and "The Gentlewoman" respectively. Both of these periodicals were published in London during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.
Scope and Contents
This is a collection of 64 letters addressed to Goddard and Wood. Notable correspondents include Edwin Lester Arnold, F.C. Burnand, Hall Caine, Sir F. Carruthers Goulde, Lillie Langtry, Clotilde Graves and Gertrude Kingston. Most of the correspondence pertains to the periodicals and specific articles within them.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in May 1959 at the recommendation of Rice History Professor Hardin Craig.
Index Terms
Subjects
Periodicals; Journalism -- England; Authors
Subjects (Persons)
Beresford, Charles William De la Poer Beresford, Baron; Black, William; Corelli, Marie; Dilke, Charles Wentworth, Sir; Gould, Francis Carruthers; Graves, Clotilde Inez Mary; Hollingshead, John; Irving, Henry; Jones, Henry Arthur; Kingston, Gertrude; Langtry, Lillie; Littlechild, John George; Marryat, Florence; Moore, Frank Frankfort; Caine, Hall, Sir; Sambourne, Linley; Toole, John Lawrence; Ward, Genevieve; Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), 1836-1917; Arnold, Edwin Lester Linden; Barrett, Wilson; Austin, Alfred
- Series I: Correspondence, 39987
  - 1884 March 2 - Sir Roger Tichborne to Arthur Goddard; handwritten note, signed, 40032 (Letter 1)
  - 1886 January 12 - H. Irving to Arthur Goddard; handwritten note, signed, 40031 (Letter 2)
  - 1887 July 16-[Linley Sambourne] to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40030 (Letter 3)
  - 1887 November 18-Frederick Leighton to Arthur Goddard, handwritten letter, signed, 40029 (Letter 4)
  - 1887 December 10-Henry Arthur Jones to Arthur Goddard, handwritten letter, signed, 40028 (Letter 5)
  - 1890 September 25-[illegible] to Arthur Goddard; handwritten note and envelope, signed, 40027 (Letter 6)
  - 1890 September 28-[illegible] to Arthur Goddard; handwritten note and envelope, signed, 40026 (Letter 7)
  - 1890 October 2-Linley Sambourne to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40025 (Letter 8)
  - 1890 October 3-Charles Warner to My Dear Sir, handwritten letter, signed, 40024 (Letter 9)
  - 1890 November 14-Charles Grisham to Arthur Goddard; typed letter, signed, 40023 (Letter 10)
  - 1890 November 28-[illegible] to "Dear Sir"; handwritten card, signed, 40022 (Letter 11)
  - 1891 January 27-Helen Reeves to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 40021 (Letter 12)
  - 1891 April 24-Henry J. Lucy to J.S. Wood; handwritten card, signed, 40020 (Letter 13)
  - 1891 April 28-[illegible] to Arthur Goddard; handwritten letter and envelope, signed, 40019 (Letter 14)
  - 1891 May 6-Wilson Barrett to Arthur Goddard; handwritten letter, signed, 40018 (Letter 15)
  - 1891 July 22-Henry Arthur Jones to [unspecified]; handwritten note, signed, 40017 (Letter 16)
  - 1891 September 24-Edwin Lester Arnold to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter; signed, 40016 (Letter 17)
  - 1892 January 29-J.L. Toole to J.S. Wood; handwritten note, signed, 40015 (Letter 18)
  - 1892 February 16-[Anset] Scott to J.S. Wood; handwritten note, signed, 40014 (Letter 19)
  - 1892 July 9-G.M. Fenn to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40013 (Letter 20)
  - 1892 August 31-Charles Beresford to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40012 (Letter 21)
  - 1893 April 29-J.G. Littlechild to Arthur Goddard; handwritten letter, signed, 40011 (Letter 22)
  - 1893 June 25-John [Jenniet] to J.S. Wood; handwritten note, signed, 40010 (Letter 23)
  - 1894 April 8-F. Frankfort Moore to "My Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 40009 (Letter 24)
  - 1894 April 15-Marie Corelli to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 40008 (Letter 25)
  - 1894 May 2 -Richard Pryce to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40007 (Letter 26)
  - 1895 April 12-Peg [Macfuord] to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 40006 (Letter 27)
  - 1895 May 23-F. Frankfurt Moore to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40005 (Letter 28)
  - 1895 September 20-Henry Francis to "Mr. Wood"; handwritten letter, signed, 40004 (Letter 29)
  - 1895 September 21-Mary St. Leger Harrison to "Dear Madame"; handwritten letter, signed, 40003 (Letter 30)
  - 1896 July 15-John Hollingshead to J.S. Wood; handwritten note card, signed, 40002 (Letter 31)
  - 1896 December 20 -Alfred Austin to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 40001 (Letter 32)
  - 1896 December 26-William Black to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 40000 (Letter 33)
  - 1898 September 24-Florence Marryat to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 39999 (Letter 34)
  - 1898 October 27-W.H. Kendal to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter, signed, 39998 (Letter 35)
  - 1899 April 24-Charles Dilke to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 39997 (Letter 36)
  - 1899 May 10-Ella Russell to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter, signed, 39996 (Letter 37)
  - 1900 July 5-F. Frankfurt Moore to Arthur Goddard; handwritten letter, signed, 39995 (Letter 38)
  - 1900 July 10-M [Hase] Pemberton to J.S. Wood; handwritten note, signed, 39994 (Letter 39)
  - 1903 July 20-F. Carruthers Gould to "My Dear Wood"; handwritten letter, signed, 39993 (Letter 40)
  - 1908 April 13-Lillie Langtry to "Dear Sir"; typed letter, signed, 39992 (Letter 41)
  - 1908 October 18-Marie Corelli to "Dear Sir"; handwritten letter and envelope, signed, 39991 (Letter 42)
  - 1909 October 14-Hall Caine to "Editor of the Lady's Pictorial"; typed letter, signed, 39990 (Letter 43)
  - 1913 March 23-Clotilde Graves to Arthur Goddard; handwritten letter, signed, 39989 (Letter 44)
  - 1917 April 4-Genevieve Ward to J.S. Wood; handwritten letter and "To My Sister of the Stage" message, signed, 39988 (Letter 45)
  - xxxx July 7-F.C. Burnand to J.S. Wood, 118905 (Letter 46)
  - xxxx October 20-William Black to Arthur Goddard, 118906 (Letter 47)
  - xxxx-[Lola Cadfreys] to "Dear Sir", 118907 (Letter 48)
  - xxxx February 13-Robert Hildeus to J.S.W., 118908 (Letter 49)
  - xxxx-H.A.J. to J.S.W., 118909 (Letter 50)
  - xxxx June 3-Gertude Kingston to J.S. Wood, 118910 (Letter 51)
  - xxxx July 31-G.K to J.S.W., 118911 (Letter 52)
  - xxxx April 26-J.G.L. to A.G., 118912 (Letter 53)
  - xxxx-Phil May to Arthur Goddard, 118913 (Letter 54)
  - xxxx July 8-Jean Middlemas to J.S. Wood, 118914 (Letter 55)
  - xxxx-Antoinette Sterling to J.S.W., 118915 (Letter 56)
  - xxxx-Violet [Vantrough (Bourdin)] to J.S.W., 118916 (Letter 57)
  - xxxx-Violet [Vantrough (Bourdin)] to J.S.W., 118917 (Letter 58)
  - xxxx-Ella Wheeler Wilcox to "Dir Sir", 118918 (Letter 59)
  - xxxx-Wilson Barrett to (unknown), 118919 (Letter 60)
  - xxxx November 1-Wilson Barrett to Arthur Goddard, 118920 (Letter 61)
  - xxxx September 16-Haddon Chamber to Arthur Goddarad, 118921 (Letter 62)
  - xxxx-Marie Corelli to "Dear Sir", 118922 (Letter 63)
  - xxxx-Frankhall to J.S.W., 118923 (Letter 64)